<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Yuliia Kostrikova</title>
    <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yuliia Kostrikova</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:30:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliakostrikova.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>k8s cluster on Raspberry PI&#39;s with iSCSI block storage</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/iscsi_pxe_mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:30:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/iscsi_pxe_mount/</guid>
      <description>exploring the challenges of running a k8s cluster on Raspberry PI&amp;#39;s with PXE network boot and overcoming containerd storage limitations using iSCSI</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detailed HowTo: PXE boot multiple RPi (Birthday Edition 🍰)</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/pxe-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:28:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/pxe-boot/</guid>
      <description>PXE (Preboot eXecution Environment) is a client-server environment which makes possible to boot and install operating systems without the need of physical media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a DHCP Server on Synology NAS in a UniFi Dream Machine SE Subnet</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/dhcp-nas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 11:28:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/dhcp-nas/</guid>
      <description>UniFi Dream Machine In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the process of setting up a DHCP server on your Synology NAS within a subnet created on a UniFi Dream Machine Special Edition (UDM SE).
Synology NAS Prerequisites Before we start, ensure you have the following:
UDM SE: UniFi Dream Machine Special Edition. Synology NAS: Network Attached Storage device from Synology. Raspberry Pi: Any model will suffice. Ethernet cables: To connect your devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPI 5 on Ubuntu 24.04 (Headless): Connect to WiFi / Mobile Hotspot</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/mobile-hotspot-on-rpi5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 11:28:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/mobile-hotspot-on-rpi5/</guid>
      <description>RPI 5 on Ubuntu 24.04 (headless): Connect to WiFi / Mobile Hotspot Introduction In my free time, I enjoy tinkering with my home lab, exploring new projects and challenges. Recently, I decided to connect my Raspberry Pi 5 to a mobile hotspot—a seemingly straightforward task. However, it turned out not so smooth. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through how I resolved the error brcmfmac: brcmf_set_channel: set chanspec fail, reason -52 and successfully connected Raspberry Pi to a mobile hotspot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating UML Diagrams with ChatGPT and PlantUML</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/chatgpt/plantuml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 13:05:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/chatgpt/plantuml/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to effortlessly visualize system designs, saving time on syntax and focusing on architecting solutions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAA-C03:: AWS Storage. EBS &amp; EFS</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/saa-c03/ebs_efs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 19:35:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/saa-c03/ebs_efs/</guid>
      <description>Study Notes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAA-C03:: Simple Storage Service (S3)</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/saa-c03/s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 15:35:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/saa-c03/s3/</guid>
      <description>Study Notes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAA-C03:: Introduction to Cloud Computing and AWS</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/saa-c03/aws-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 19:35:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/saa-c03/aws-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Study Notes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Mount Synology NAS to RaspberryPi via NFS</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/ovderride-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 11:28:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/homelab/ovderride-provider/</guid>
      <description>My Use case To establish a seamless synchronization of project files between a MacBook (working station) and a Raspberry Pi (hosting server), allowing for automatic updates and accessibility of the project from both devices.
device/tool version DS420+ DSM 7.2-64570 Raspberry PI 400 The user begins working on the project using the IDE on the MacBook, editing and updating project files within the synchronized folder. As changes are made, they are automatically reflected in the synchronized folder and accessible on the Raspberry Pi in read-only mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traefik behind AWS ELB. X-Forwarded-For header</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/cloud/traefik-x-forwarded-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 18:02:25 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/cloud/traefik-x-forwarded-for/</guid>
      <description>Traefik v1.7 is running within a Docker Swarm, functioning as a global service. Consequently, an instance of Traefik is deployed for each host within our Docker Swarm cluster. It is important to note that the Swarm&amp;rsquo;s routing mesh is not employed in this setup. Instead, the port mode is configured as &amp;ldquo;host,&amp;rdquo; allowing the port to be attached to the host&amp;rsquo;s network.
traefik: image: ${REGISTRY}/traefik:1.6 build: ./traefik volumes: - /var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock networks: - traefik environment: - AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID=${AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID} - AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY=${AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY} - AWS_REGION=${AWS_REGION} - AWS_HOSTED_ZONE_ID=${AWS_HOSTED_ZONE_ID} ports: - target: 80 published: 80 protocol: tcp mode: host - target: 443 published: 443 mode: host protocol: tcp - target: 8080 published: 8080 mode: host protocol: tcp deploy: mode: global restart_policy: condition: on-failure Docker Swarm deployed to AWS and lives behind internal/external load balancers (Classic type).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom error page in Traefik v2.x. Finally</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/cloud/traefik-error-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 18:02:25 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/cloud/traefik-error-page/</guid>
      <description>What you will learn today 🦦: what is Traefik and why I decisively recommend to use it with Docker Swarm how to show custom error page if Traefik returns 404 (service not found) How I met Traefik 😁 Traefik is a top modern reverse proxy and load balancer. I started to use it from major version 1. At that moment, I already had Docker Swarm cluster, which I began to prepare for production use, and only one thing in the coherent picture has been left: &amp;ldquo;External Load Balancer&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solution for CodeSignal: addTwoHugeNumbers (Linked List part 👯)</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/algorithms/addtwohugenumbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 15:35:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/algorithms/addtwohugenumbers/</guid>
      <description>Task description on Codesignal
I’ve spend decent amount of time in order to figure out that I don’t need any string manipulation in this task 😅. My first try was adding missing zeros to the beginning of number slot, convert int to str and back, then the resulting string split by 4 but no luck … It turned out that is simple math 😀 I wanna share my solution with detailed comments ⬇️ (Time complexity O(n) )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to analyse “high CPU” in php on production. Part 1</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/php/high-cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 18:56:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/php/high-cpu/</guid>
      <description>How to analyse “high CPU” in php on production. Part 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XDebug for PHP docker container on macOS</title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/php/xdebug-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 18:56:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/php/xdebug-macos/</guid>
      <description>How to guide: Configure remote debugging with XDebug for php docker container on macOS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/misc/auto-rollout-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliakostrikova.com/posts/misc/auto-rollout-terraform/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
